<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="1435" offered="Y">
<term term_pattern_code="1" fall_term="Y" spring_term="N">fall term</term>
<department code="DEAS">
<dept_long_name>Division of Engineering and Applied Sciences</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>Engineering and Applied Sciences</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="COMPSCI">Computer Science</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>279</num_int>
</course_number>
<title>Research Topics in Human-Computer Interaction</title>
<course_type>Lecture</course_type>
<course_level code="T">Primarily for Graduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<meeting_text>Tu., Th., 10-11:30</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>Krzysztof Z. Gajos</faculty_text>
<description>The course covers major areas of inquiry and core research methods in Human-Computer Interaction including experimental design, statistical data analysis, and qualitative methods. Activities will include discussion of primary literature, a small number of lectures, assignments (design, execution and analysis of both lab-based and on-line experiments), and a research project. Special focus this year is on social computing and crowd-powered systems. Specifically, we will look at the design and analysis of systems, in which crowds of intrinsically motivated volunteers contribute to meaningful and non-trivial human computation tasks as a byproduct of doing something that they are motivated to do anyway.</description>
<prerequisites>None for graduate students; for undergrads CS 179 or CS 171 is strongly recommended and permission of the instructor is required. Basic web hacking is required to implement and deploy web-based experiments.</prerequisites>
<notes>Designed for first year grads from all areas. Advanced undergraduates welcome, particularly those who wish to do research (or write a thesis) in an area related to Human-Computer Interaction.</notes>
<instructor_approval_required>Y</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="1" role="H" id="Fc1f06adf0423e998132e85b26c01c824">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Krzysztof</first>
<middle>Z</middle>
<last>Gajos</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="2" begin_time="1000" end_time="1130"/>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="4" begin_time="1000" end_time="1130"/>
</schedule>
<meeting_locations>
<location term="1" building="Maxwell Dworkin" room="319" type="Lecture"/>
</meeting_locations>
<requirements/>
</course></courses>