<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="1065" offered="Y">
<term term_pattern_code="2" fall_term="N" spring_term="Y">spring term</term>
<department code="GEN ED">
<dept_long_name>Committee on General Education</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>General Education</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="CULTR&amp;BLF">Culture and Belief</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>19</num_int>
</course_number>
<title>Understanding Islam and Contemporary Muslim Societies</title>
<course_type>Lecture with sections</course_type>
<course_level code="P">Primarily for Undergraduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<meeting_text>Tu., 7:40-9:40 p.m., and a weekly section to be arranged.</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>Ali S. Asani (Study of Religion; Near Eastern Languages and Civilizations)</faculty_text>
<description>The course is an introduction to the fundamental concepts of Islam and the role that religious ideas and institutions play in Muslim communities around the world. Its main concern is to develop an understanding of the manner in which diverse notions of religious and political authority have influenced Muslim societies politically, socially and culturally. Through specific case studies of countries such as Saudi Arabia, Iran, Turkey, Egypt, Pakistan, and Afghanistan, the course considers the role played by ideologies such as jihad, colonialism, nationalism, secularism, and globalization in shaping the ways in which Muslims interpret and practice their faith today. The course briefly considers the contemporary situation of Muslim minorities in Europe and the United States. The course, through on-campus and on-line options, allows those enrolled to engage with students from all over the world.</description>
<prerequisites/>
<notes>Offered jointly with the Divinity School as 3628. This course fulfills the requirement that one of the eight General Education courses also engage substantially with Study of the Past.</notes>
<instructor_approval_required>N</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="2" role="H" id="Fb734a65a5e0b66fad7b18d12f2eab69d">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Ali</first>
<middle/>
<last>Asani</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="2" begin_time="1940" end_time="2140"/>
</schedule>
<meeting_locations/>
<requirements>
<requirement type="Core Curriculum" name="Foreign Cultures"/>
<requirement type="Core Curriculum" name="Historical Study A"/>
<requirement type="General Education" name="Culture and Belief"/>
<requirement type="General Education" name="Study of the Past"/>
</requirements>
</course></courses>