<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="12763" offered="N" next_year_offered="2015">
<term term_pattern_code="2" fall_term="N" spring_term="Y">spring term</term>
<department code="GERM">
<dept_long_name>Department of Germanic Languages and Literatures</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>Germanic Languages and Literatures</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="GERMAN">German</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>146</num_int>
</course_number>
<title>The Ethics of Atheism: Marx, Nietzsche, Freud</title>
<course_type>Lecture</course_type>
<course_level code="O">For Undergraduates and Graduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<meeting_text>Hours to be arranged.</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>Peter J. Burgard</faculty_text>
<description>Examines the Western secular tradition through the work of three seminal figures whose critiques of religion - in social and political theory, philosophy, and psycho-analysis and anthropology - are motivated by ethical concerns. Introductory readings of Kant, Hegel, and Feuerbach ground analysis of Marx's, Nietzsche's, and Freud's ethical atheism. Students do not develop or debate formulae for behavior, but rather become critically aware of ethical considerations that underlie actions and that are negotiated vis-a-vis prevailing moral codes. Readings include The German Ideology, The Communist Manifesto, The Gay Science, Beyond Good and Evil, On the Genealogy of Morals, The Anti-Christ, Three Essays on the Theory of Sexuality, Totem and Taboo, The Future of an Illusion.</description>
<prerequisites/>
<notes>This course, when taken for a letter grade, meets the General Education requirement for Ethical Reasoning or Culture and Belief, but not both. No knowledge of German required. All readings and discussions in English. Not open to auditors.</notes>
<instructor_approval_required>N</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="2" role="H" id="Fdd5da5e35720279c6f118465599d4e59">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Peter</first>
<middle>J.</middle>
<last>Burgard</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule/>
<meeting_locations/>
<requirements>
<requirement type="Core Curriculum" name="Moral Reasoning"/>
<requirement type="General Education" name="Culture and Belief"/>
<requirement type="General Education" name="Ethical Reasoning"/>
</requirements>
</course></courses>