<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="6062" offered="Y">
<term term_pattern_code="1" fall_term="Y" spring_term="N">fall term</term>
<department code="MDSC">
<dept_long_name>Division of Medical Sciences</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>Medical Sciences</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="NEUROBIO">Neurobiology</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>200</num_int>
</course_number>
<title>Neurobiology</title>
<course_type>Lecture</course_type>
<course_level code="T">Primarily for Graduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<enrollment_limit>50</enrollment_limit>
<meeting_text>M., W., 8:30&amp;#8211;12, F., 8:30&amp;#8211;10:30</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>John A. Assad (Medical School), Matthew P. Frosch (Medical School), Jeffrey Robb Holt (Medical School), Rosalind A. Segal (Medical School), and Ziv Williams (Medical School)</faculty_text>
<description>This is a comprehensive course in Neuroscience. Basic principles of organization and function of the nervous system will be discussed with frequent reference to pathophysiology of neurological and psychiatric disorders. Combining pathophysiology with basic neuroscience should provide physician/scientists and Ph.D. candidates with a dynamic picture of the rapidly evolving field of neuroscience and the experimental process from which the picture is derived, and all students should emerge with a greater awareness both of the applications of their work in alleviating disease, and of the ways that disease can provide insight into basic scientific questions. The course will span modern neuroscience from molecular neurobiology to perception and cognition, and will include the following major topics: Anatomy and Development of the Brain; Cell Biology of Neurons and Glia; Ion Channels and Electrical Signaling; Synaptic Transmission, Integration, and Chemical Systems of the Brain; Sensory Systems, from Transduction to Perception; Motor Systems; and Higher Brain Function (Memory, Language, Affective Disorders).</description>
<prerequisites>Introductory cell and molecular biology course and permission of instructor.</prerequisites>
<notes>Offered jointly with the Medical School as HT 130. Follows the Medical School calendar. Nine hours of lecture or lab/conference weekly.</notes>
<instructor_approval_required>N</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="1" role="H" id="F329cdb7a6460a7206ce66261679bc359">
<name>
<prefix>Dr.</prefix>
<first>John</first>
<middle>A.</middle>
<last>Assad</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="1" begin_time="830" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="3" begin_time="830" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="5" begin_time="830" end_time="1030"/>
</schedule>
<meeting_locations/>
<requirements/>
</course></courses>