<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="45382" offered="Y">
<term term_pattern_code="1" fall_term="Y" spring_term="N">fall term</term>
<department code="PSYC">
<dept_long_name>Department of Psychology</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>Psychology</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="PSY">Psychology</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>980</num_int>
<num_char>u</num_char>
</course_number>
<title>Psychological Challenges of Adolescence and Early Adulthood</title>
<course_type>Seminar</course_type>
<course_level code="P">Primarily for Undergraduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<enrollment_limit>16</enrollment_limit>
<meeting_text>W., 7:30-9:30 p.m.</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>Mahzarin Banaji and members of the Department</faculty_text>
<description>This seminar will examine research on a wide range of developmental, social, and psychological processes that affect the mental health of adolescents and young adults. We will discuss factors that facilitate resilience during adolescence and the transition to adulthood (such as personality traits and economic resources), as well as risk factors (such as parental maltreatment and exposure to violence). We will also explore questions specific to disorders common during this developmental period, such as whether adolescent mood and anxiety disorders are unidimensional or bideminsional constructs, and how recent social and neurobiological research can enhance our understanding of the unique challenges faced by adolescents and young adults with ADHD. Throughout the course, we will discuss research on emerging trends in media use and Facebook, and the impact of these technologies on depression, anxiety, substance abuse, and cyberbullying.</description>
<prerequisites>Science of Living Systems 20 and PSY 18.</prerequisites>
<notes/>
<instructor_approval_required>Y</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="1" role="H" id="F915b0ed348ff3b904d5fa0f461ab8f26">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Mahzarin</first>
<middle>R.</middle>
<last>Banaji</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Seminar" day="3" begin_time="1930" end_time="2130"/>
</schedule>
<meeting_locations>
<location term="1" building="William James Hall" room="4" type="Seminar"/>
</meeting_locations>
<requirements/>
</course></courses>