<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="40372" offered="N" next_year_offered="2015">
<term term_pattern_code="2" fall_term="N" spring_term="Y">spring term</term>
<department code="RELG">
<dept_long_name>Committee on the Study of Religion</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>The Study of Religion</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="RELIGION">Religion</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>1519</num_int>
</course_number>
<title>American Religious History Since 1865</title>
<course_type>Lecture</course_type>
<course_level code="O">For Undergraduates and Graduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<meeting_text>Tu., Th., 10&amp;#8211;11:30 and an hour to be arranged.</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>----------</faculty_text>
<description>This course is a survey of American religion from Reconstruction to the present. We will ask several related questions. How did religious communities shape social and political movements like women's suffrage, the anti-lynching campaign, the Civil Rights Movement, and second-wave feminism? How did religious communities respond to developments like urbanization, segregation, industrialization, the Great Depression, and the creation of new media? How did ordinary people practice their faith? We will discuss a wide variety of religious communities and movements, including the Social Gospel, Catholicism, Fundamentalism, Judaism, Pentecostalism, New Thought, and the Christian Right. We will also discuss the transformation of the American religious landscape after the 1965 Immigration and Nationality Act. In addition to reading major scholarly accounts, we will consult a wide variety of primary sources, including memoirs, sermons, religious periodicals, speeches, and music.</description>
<prerequisites/>
<notes>Offered jointly with the Divinity School as 2376.</notes>
<instructor_approval_required>N</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list/>
<schedule/>
<meeting_locations/>
<requirements/>
</course></courses>