<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="41571" offered="Y">
<term term_pattern_code="4" fall_term="Y" spring_term="Y">full year</term>
<department code="SLAV">
<dept_long_name>Department of Slavic Languages and Literatures</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>Slavic Languages and Literatures</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="PLSH">Polish</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_char>B</num_char>
</course_number>
<title>Intermediate Polish</title>
<course_type>Lecture with sections</course_type>
<course_level code="O">For Undergraduates and Graduates</course_level>
<credit code="2">Full course</credit>
<meeting_text>M., W., F., at 11, with an additional hour of speaking practice to be arranged.</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>Anna Baranczak</faculty_text>
<description>An intermediate course in modern Polish language and culture for students with previous study of the language. Further development of vocabulary and oral expression within a comprehensive review of Polish grammar. All four major communicative skills (speaking, listening comprehension, reading, writing) are stressed as students learn to use the language both as a means of communication and as a tool for reading and research. Introduction to Polish literature through fiction and poetry, history and contemporary events, including readings from literary masterpieces from Polish literature from the era of the Renaissance to contemporary times including Jan Kochanowski, Wisl\a-awa Szymborska, Zbigniew Herbert, Czesl\a-aw Mil\a-osz and others. Film clips and newspaper articles will introduce students to a variety of styles of contemporary Polish. Systematic study of word formation and other strategies are taught to help free students from excessive dependence on the dictionary and develop confidence in reading. This year-long full course prepares students for continued study of Polish in advanced-level courses and for study or travel abroad in Poland.</description>
<prerequisites>Polish A or placement at the B-level. Familiarity with fundamentals of Polish grammar, particularly case endings and elementary competence in spoken Polish.</prerequisites>
<notes/>
<instructor_approval_required>N</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="1" role="H" id="F71a16ddea4fd71a8adf0b9e4d938cae6">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Anna</first>
<middle/>
<last>Baranczak</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
<faculty term="2" role="H" id="F71a16ddea4fd71a8adf0b9e4d938cae6">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Anna</first>
<middle/>
<last>Baranczak</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="1" begin_time="1100" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="3" begin_time="1100" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="1" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="5" begin_time="1100" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="1" begin_time="1100" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="3" begin_time="1100" end_time="1200"/>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="5" begin_time="1100" end_time="1200"/>
</schedule>
<meeting_locations>
<location term="1" building="Barker Center" room="BarkerCtr_328" type="Lecture"/>
</meeting_locations>
<requirements/>
</course></courses>