<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><courses><course acad_year="2014" cat_num="24022" offered="Y">
<term term_pattern_code="2" fall_term="N" spring_term="Y">spring term</term>
<department code="CHEM">
<dept_long_name>Department of Chemistry and Chemical Biology</dept_long_name>
<dept_short_name>Chemistry and Chemical Biology</dept_short_name>
</department>
<course_group code="PHYSCI">Physical Sciences</course_group>
<course_number>
<num_int>11</num_int>
</course_number>
<title>Foundations and Frontiers of Modern Chemistry: A Molecular and Global Perspective</title>
<course_type>Lecture and Lab</course_type>
<course_level code="P">Primarily for Undergraduates</course_level>
<credit code="1">Half course</credit>
<meeting_text>M., W., F., at 10 and a weekly section and lab to be arranged.</meeting_text>
<faculty_text>James G. Anderson and Gregory C. Tucci</faculty_text>
<description>The Physical Sciences hold the key to solving unprecedented problems at the intersection of science, technology, and an array of rapidly emerging global scale challenges. The course emphasizes a molecular scale understanding of energy and entropy; free energy in equilibria, acid/base reactivity, and electrochemistry; molecular bonding and kinetics; catalysis in organic and inorganic systems; the union of quantum mechanics, nanostructures, and photovoltaics; and the analysis of nuclear energy. Case studies are used both to develop quantitative reasoning and to directly link these principles to global strategies.</description>
<prerequisites>A strong background in chemistry. Students are expected to have had Honors or AP-level high school chemistry preparation or a placement score of 650 or better on the Harvard Chemistry Placement exam. A few operations of calculus are developed and used. Fluency in pre-calculus secondary school mathematics is assumed.</prerequisites>
<notes>Physical Sciences 10 and Physical Sciences 11 may be taken in any order. The general chemistry requirement for medical students can be satisfied with any two of the following courses: Life and Physical Sciences A, Life Sciences 1a, Physical Sciences 1, Physical Sciences 10, or Physical Sciences 11. This course, when taken for a letter grade, meets the General Education requirement for Science of the Physical Universe. NOTE: Physical Sciences 1 and Physical Sciences 11 cannot both be taken for credit.</notes>
<instructor_approval_required>N</instructor_approval_required>
<faculty_list>
<faculty term="2" role="H" id="F5f54e8708840989bc525ae860c6bd6a8">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>James</first>
<middle>G.</middle>
<last>Anderson</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
<faculty term="2" role="O" id="F6752a1cf1553e62728467d662882ff7e">
<name>
<prefix/>
<first>Gregory</first>
<middle/>
<last>Tucci</last>
<suffix/>
</name>
</faculty>
</faculty_list>
<schedule>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="1" begin_time="1000" end_time="1100"/>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="3" begin_time="1000" end_time="1100"/>
<meeting term="2" optional="N" type="Lecture" day="5" begin_time="1000" end_time="1100"/>
</schedule>
<meeting_locations/>
<requirements>
<requirement type="Core Curriculum" name="Science A"/>
<requirement type="General Education" name="Science of the Physical Universe"/>
</requirements>
</course></courses>